Dmitry Kustov





Career goal

I've been working in technical support and application management for 15 years, but I'm passionate about gaming and want to contribute to making more games. My goal is to specialize in designing compelling narratives, but I'm also open to other design roles, quality assurance, and support positions. I work at a slower pace when coding, but I'm still eager to explore new development opportunities that allow me to work at a comfortable pace without compromising on quality.

Core competencies

- Technical Support | Incident Management | Problem Management | Quality Assurance | Product Ownership | Change Control | Automation | Storytelling | Creativity
- Web Development | Fullstack Development | Business Analysis | Project Management | Risk Management | Disaster Recovery | Security | Customer Success | Communication | Coaching
- Teadership | Software Architecture | UI/UX Design | Graphics Editing | Video Editing

Languages

- VBScript | VBA | VB.NET | GameMaker
- Windows CLI | PowerShell | Python | C# | C++ | Finnish | German

Tech tools and concepts

- MS Excel | MS Outlook | MS Word | MS PowerPoint | PHPStorm | MySQL | ServiceNow | REST
- Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Premiere | Oracle | MS SQL | Windows | Windows Server | Jira | Confluence | Data Architecture | GameMaker
- Apache HTTPD | LiteSpeed | Microservices | Agile | SharePoint | GameMaker

For some of the skills' assessments visit

▶Pluralsight

Education

10/2023 – 01/2024: Security Journey 📃

01/2023 – 05/2023: Arcada, Game Design and Production 📃

12/2020 – 12/2020: 🗓 Basics of Web-Services Support 📃

09/2006 – 06/2011: ☐ Moscow Institute of Electronics and Mathematics, Management & Informatics in Technical Systems ☐

Dmitry Kustov

Professional experience

04/2023 – current: R&D Support Engineer, Signant Health, Helsinki, Finland

💢 Investigate, manage, and triage application incidents and service requests.

- Submitted almost a hundred suggestions for product improvement within first month.
- ✓ Helped with several de-escalations of issues with sponsors.
- Wrote multiple knowledgebase articles.

09/2021 – 06/2022: Tier 3 Technical Support Engineer, Smartly.io, Helsinki, Finland

- X Ensured best-in-class technical support and distinguished customer service with lots of analysis and debugging.
- X Kept product documentation up to date.
- X Assisted and trained teammates.

- Drove implementation of Support Handbook, internal collection of manuals and guidelines for customer support.
- Earned Snapchat essentials certificate.
- Participated in leadership training.

06/2009 - 07/2021: Application Manager / Senior Technical Support Analyst, Citi, Moscow

- Managed up to 30 applications with scope similar to product/project manager.
- Debugged new issues and tested new or changed features on a regular basis.
- 🔀 Lead or participated in processes' automation and/or optimization projects.
- Provided L1, L2 and L3 tech support and change control for most of Russian and Kazakhstan applications.
- 🔀 Lead tech support operators, when in absence of direct manager.
- Coached new tech support operators.
- 💢 Developed and maintained internal documentation, server-side and GUI-based automations (scripts).

- Transferred paper-based checklist used by support operators to MS Excel, with automations, traceability, reporting, and statistics gathering (AutomatedRunSheet).
- Single-handedly managed all tech-related questions for Kazakhstan for 2 years.
- Almost completely cleared a decade-long backlog for Kazakhstan applications in roughly a year.
- Pioneered huge refactoring of a client-facing application, to implement **E-Documents** concept, while negotiating the initial vendor price from \$100k down to \$55k USD.
- Participated in "Want to be a leader" training.

02/2009 – 03/2009: Engineer, Windsor, Moscow, Russia

- 💢 Managed office hardware and software.
- 💢 Managed company's website.
- Created digital training courses.

Dmitry Kustov

Page | 3

Personal projects

02/2023 – current: Dangerous Dave: Endless Nightmare

A homage to "Dangerous Dave in the Haunted Mansion", that started as part of Game Design and Production course's bootcamp.

10/2022 - current: Support from HEL

Sharing knowledge about and around tech support with fellow supporters in support community.

12/2021 – current: Simbiat Software

Open-source project written from scratch with a goal of a system for creation of interactive story-telling experiences (visual novels and text-based RPG games) and community around it. Also functions as a personal blog, which includes some game-related <u>articles</u> (with some of them being analytical).

03/2023 - 05/2023: Radical Resonance

A game done from scratch as final assignment for Arcada's Game Design and Production course.

02/2023 - 03/2023: Jiangshi

A game done as part of retheming game jam for Arcada's Game Design and Production course.

03/2020 - 09/2021: Aqua Chronica

Filmed and edited a series of videos describing journey of offices fishes to my home.

04/2017 - 12/2021: BIC Tracker

PHP-based web-service aimed at tracking changes in Bank Identification Codes library provided by Russian Central Bank, while also representing the original DBF (later XML) format as human-readable pages.

09/2016 - 12/2021: Final Fantasy XIV Tracker

PHP-based web-service aimed at tracking <u>Final Fantasy XIV</u> characters and free companies. Merged into Simbiat Software. Also filmed <u>Welcome to My Crib</u> during the same time.

02/2014 - 02/2015: **DarkSteam**

VB.NET-based client for <u>Steam</u>'s metadata exchange utilizing <u>Serv-U</u>'s SFTP, <u>vBulletin</u> forum engine and custom PHP scripts. Had ~200 active users and earned ~\$450 monthly donations. Stopped due to failed attempt of utilizing torrent seed-box and Steam's metadata no longer being in a "gray" area of the license agreement.

09/2006 – 02/2014: A12 FTP Server

A <u>Serv-U</u> based server used for local network file-sharing with total capacity over 8TBs.

11/2005 – 01/2016: Prose and poetry

Various attempts at writing prose and poetry, including 4 attempts to write a whole book.

09/2004 – 09/2006: ElderScrolls.lan

Local network website based on PHP-Nuke and PHPBB, accumulating (and translating) various information about The Elder Scrolls game series.